English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library, circa 1000-1820: First-line index.
English-language manuscript verse in the Houghton Library circa 1000-1820,
- Baillie, Joanna. Alterations to adapt the tragedy of Rayner for representation, undated., MS Eng 619
- The battle of Otterbourne: two versions from manuscripts in the British Museum, [before 1876], MS Eng 1499
  Transcribed from British Library, MSS Harl. 293, fol. 52, and Cott. Cleo. C-iv, fol. 64
- [Ballads, poems, songs, satyres, epitaphs etc. of the time of Charles II; 19??], MS Eng 633
- Basilius Valentinus. Philosopher's Stone; Alchemical treatises and poems, undated., MS Eng 1488
- Black, W. H. MSS notes. 1826-1835., MS Eng 534
  Packets of unfoliated pamphlets and academic notes by William Henry Black from British Library MSS
- Bliss, Philip. MSS notes from Ashmolean Museum. [18??], MS Eng 540
  A collection of unfoliated papers and notebooks.
- Bowles, William L. Autograph letters and proofs, undated., MS Eng 505 and 505.5
  Unfoliated letters and papers.
- The Caliph of Bagdad, a comic opera in two acts, undated., MS Mus 237
  Act II only.
- Breton, Nicholas. Poems, undated., MS Eng 1495
  Photostats from British Library MS Add. 34064
- Bridges, Nathaniel. Commonplace book: on angling, 1694-1717., MS Eng 1490
  Contains some poems.
- Poems, undated., MS Eng 1494
  Photostats from British Library MS Harl. 7392
- Buchan, Peter. Collection, 1823-1900., MS Eng 1491 (4)
  2 vols. of Scots ballads, copied under Francis Child's direction from Peter Buchan MSS in the British Library
- Buchan, Peter. Collection, 1823-1900., MS Eng 1491 (3)
  Peter Buchan's collection of ballads, copied from recitation and old MSS
- Byron, [George Gordon Byron] The gaiour. [With extracts from Byron's works and miscellaneous poems. Commonplace book] 1814., MS Eng 630
- Byron, George Gordon Byron. English bards and Scotch reviewers, [after 1811], MS Eng 1484
- Ballads, [before 1876], MS Eng 1496
  John Hill Burton's transcript of ballads from MSS.
- Byron, George Gordon Byron. The curse of Minerva, 1815., MS Eng 1485
- Old Scottish songs: collected in the counties of Berwick, Roxburgh, Selkirk & Peebles, 1883., MS Eng 1497
  2 vols. of Scottish poems and ballads compiled by Sir Hugh Hume Campbell.
- Chaucer, G. Troilus - copied from British Library MSS. Ps. M. MS 12044 and Harl. MS 2392, [1894?], MS Eng 538
- Chaucer, G. Troilus - copied from British Library MSS. [1894?], MS Eng 537
- The child of Bristow, [18??], MS Eng 1508
  Manuscript of Francis Child's edn.
- Clare, John. Pastoral fancies, undated., MS Eng 1487
- Child, Francis James. English and Scottish popular ballad research materials, 1849-1914., MS Am 2349
  Child MSS of ballad variants - 32 vols. Vols. 1-20 are paginated, and Seng follows the page numbers. Vols. 21-30 are foliated in the upper right corner, and for these Seng uses the foliations
- Cumberlege, B. Misc. poems by several hands, 1703., MS Eng 584
- Unidentified., [None]
- [Collection of satirical ballads and poems in the time of Charles I] undated., MS Eng 585
- Cornwallis, William. The contrition of a convertite; Heavenly hymne, undated., MS Eng 1493
- [Commonplace book] [16??-17??], MS Eng 586
- Colderidge, Samuel Taylor. Sibylline leaves, 1817., *EC. C 6795.817s (c)
  (formerly 19478.65 )
  A printed book with manuscript insertions.
- Alsop, Anthony. Aedis Christi olium..., [17??], *EC7. Ox250.702p
  (originally ML 15.2F )
  MSS bound together with printed documents; a calendar at the beginning lists the items by number; Seng uses these numbers for reference.
- Madden, Sir Frederick. Paper and extracts in nine portfolios, undated., MS Eng 527
  Folder 8, item 4: "The Vision of Paris"
- A collection of miscellaneous poems from the greatest poets, etc. [17??], MS Eng 631
- A collection of poems. [A commonplace book. Many poems by the Earl of Rochester, ca. 1680], MS Eng 636
- Harris, Amelia. Amelia Harris' collection of traditional ancient ballads and fragments, ca.1872., MS Eng 1444
- Dawes, Sir William. Poems on several occasions, transcribed from the original by C. B. [Charles Blake] [16??], MS Eng 640
- Clarke, John. [Papers relating to Dr. John Clarke] 1752-1771., MS Am 888F
  Clark papers, "The Toy Shop" by R. Dodsley
- Falkland, Lucius Cary, 2nd Viscount. An elogie on the death of ... Syr Henry Moryson. [ca. 1630.], MS Eng 635
  Falkland's "Elegy"
- Ellwood, Thomas. A hymn to God... [ca. 1800.], MS Eng 676
- Fairfax, Brian. [Poems, many original, others copies] undated., MS Eng 602
- A collection of old Scottish ballads: transcribed from Vol. XI of the Glen Riddell manuscripts, [18??], MS Eng 1500
- Christmas carrols, 1767., MS Eng 1507
- Christmas carrols, [ca. 1777], MS Eng 1507
- Webb, John. John Webb: his book, 1777., MS Eng 1507
- Humphreys, David. A poem on the national industry of the United States of America, 1792., MS Am 2374
- Transcripts and notes concerning the "Brown manuscript" of Scottish popular ballads, 1793-1920., MS Eng 1486 (2)
  Copy of Jamieson's ballads
- Kinloch, George Ritchie. Papers for Ancient Scottish ballads, 1820-1883., MS Eng 1471
  7 vols.
- Jaques, Francis. The Queene of Corsica: a tragady, 1642., MS Eng 1489
  Photostat from British Library, MS Lansdowne 807
- Laing, Alexander. Letters, verses etc. relating to Robert Archibald Smith's "Scotish minstrel", 1818., MS Eng 1505
- Lamb, Charles. Grace before Meat, undated., MS Lowell 6
- Laing, Alexander. Ancient ballads & songs etc. etc. from the recitation of old people, 1829-1843., MS Eng 1504
- Laing, Alexander. Ballads, songs, and fragments, 1873., MS Eng 1506
- A pleasant commodie called Looke about you (Look About You), undated., MS Eng 1483
- [Verses concerning the Duke of Marlborough] [17??], *EC7. M3436 Z 722c
  Entries in the index of first lines can be found in the following poems:
  To his Grace the Duke of Marlborough
  A poem on His Grace the Duke of Marlborough's going into Germany
  To his Grace the Duke of Marlborough on the present rebellion
  The plain truth
  An allusion of Horace
  A modern inscription To the Duke of Marlborough's fame
  Verses written on the mourning of the Duke of Marlborough's funeral
- Macmath, William. Scottish ballad transcripts, 1873-1896., MS Eng 1470
- Peck, Francis. Robin Hood ballads, [18??], MS Eng 1501
- Macmath, William. Scottish ballad transcripts, 1873-1896., MS Eng 1470
- Macmath, William. Scottish ballad transcripts, 1873-1896., MS Eng 1470
- "Poems on various occasions" and by several hands, 1780-[1781], MS Eng 680
- Prologues and epilogues; [16??], MS Eng 674
- Savage, Arthur. Philosophical extracts and poetry from various authors, undated., MS Eng 555
- [Poems, of a devotional character. With a transcript of part of the Eikon Basilike]; [16??], MS Eng 625
- Rolf, J, collector. Poems, tracts, and memoirs. [1700-], MS Eng 606
- [Saffin, John] An elegie on the deplored decease of... Mrs. Sarah Leveret. Copy, undated., MS Am 187.9
- [The vicar of Bray. Ballad], 1733., MS Eng 627
- Ritson, Joseph. Scottish ballads. [1793-1794], MS Eng 1486 (1)
- Macmath, William. Scottish ballad transcripts, 1873-1896., MS Eng 1470
- Macmath, William. Scottish ballad transcripts, 1873-1896., MS Eng 1470
  Charles K. Sharpe - ballads
- Transcripts and notes concerning the "Brown manuscript" of Scottish popular ballads, 1793-1920., MS Eng 1486 (3)
  Francis Child - ballads
- Macmath, William.; Charles Kirkpatrick Sharpe's "Second collection" of ballads, 1893., MS Eng 862.1
- Skene, James. Scottish ballads, [after 1803], MS Eng 1498
- Transcripts and notes concerning the "Brown manuscript" of Scottish popular ballads, 1793-1920., MS Eng 1486 (4)
  Watts - ballads
- Ballads copied from printed exemplars and manuscripts., MS Eng 1503 (1)
  Seng recorded only those copied from manuscripts.